welcome to this complete guide to
asp.net core identity course in the
first section we're going to look under
the hood of asp.net core authentication
and authorization without using identity
so that we can have a complete
understanding of how expedient court
identity works and what are the purpose
of those
objects that we're going to use in
asp.net core identity and what are the
purposes and how they achieve what they
achieve
right so this is really the under the
hood section we're gonna learn about uh
security in general right and then
authentication authorization flows uh
we're gonna learn about what are
identities what are principles right
what are what is security contacts and
then we're going to start implement
a login page we're going to generate
cookies to sustain
and remember who the user is right
remember those identities and then we're
going to read the security context from
the cookie and then we're going to learn
about how authorization works in the sp9
core
and
we're going to create policies with
claims we're going to also implement a
custom policy based authorization
scenario which we can use to cover
complicated cases
so after we understand how exactly
authentication authorization works in
asp.net core for web applications
in second section
we are moving on to securing web apis
web apis instead of using cookie
typically we use tokens so in this
section we're going to learn about
jwt tokens we're going to implement the
jwt token authentication and we're going
to learn how to encapsulate claims in jw
token we're going to implement the whole
jet lab token authentication and
authorization flows
and then we are going to also implement
authorizations
with gw tokens
in the third section this is when we
really get into espinona core identity
but with the complete understanding of
how asp.net core authentication
authorization works
it's very easy to understand how
experiment core identity works right
we're going to learn about the essential
parts of the identities we're going to
learn about what problem identity
actually
resolves uh what's the knowledge that we
have learned so far and then we're going
to configure uh expedient core identity
and we started code with asp.net core
identity to cover typical scenarios like
user registration user logging
email confirmation
signing in signing out collecting user
information
learn about rows as well as we're going
to create user profile pages and be able
to update user information and then in
the fourth section we're going to learn
about mfa we say spinner core identity
so mfa stands for multi-factor
authentication all right we're going to
learn about how it works and then we're
going to start implementing uh with
email multi-factor authentications and
then moving on to authenticator app
multi-factor authentication
all right and finally last but not least
we're going to learn about external
authentication providers i'm going to
use facebook as an example
we learn about how oauth works in
general because multi-factor
authentication
usually depends on us
right and then we're gonna create a
facebook application and then we're
gonna link our web application to
facebook and we're gonna start
implementing the delegation to facebook
so that we can complete our course
this course is definitely not just a
theory course
it contains a lot of practice a lot of
coding
by the end of the course
you will be able to understand how
exactly a speed and a core then it works
what problem it resolves and you will be
able to use every single part of asp.net
core identity to secure your web
applications to secure your web apis
please feel free to look into the course
and watch all of those free preview
videos i'm very excited to see you in my
course
in this video we're going to learn about
security on a high level so that you
have a very solid understanding of what
security really is
what are the the key concepts in
security including
the security context authentication and
authorization
let's imagine there's a military base
right there's a security guard and this
is you trying to get into the uh the
yard
okay so you go here and the security
guard will ask you to show your identity
right you cannot just say who i am
the person will not believe you so you
have to show your secu your identity
card that will actually make sense to
your to the security guard right
every person have many different type of
identities you can have your driver's
license you can have a student card you
can have an employee card but in this
case
you may have to show your identities
that is
provided to you
by the military base or by the military
units right so once verified that your
identity information is valid basically
verify that you are who you say you are
then most likely the security guard will
give you a access card so let's use this
as an example let's say this is access
card so you will have a access heart in
your hand
so let's combine this together right so
you now have a access card and this
access card contains again your identity
informations as well as some of the
other information may be including
expiry date right so you may only have
access to this
military base
for a limited period of time
so then you go into the gate
now
if you want to go into any of the
buildings
you cannot just walk in and we'll check
your
internal identity card this card that
just was given to you to verify that you
have the permission to go into each one
of these buildings
right because each different building
may have different requirements you have
to be perhaps above a certain rank or
you have to be one of the managers of
this building
then it will allow you to go in and when
the
access card expires you would have to
go out of this facility
right well you have to return your card
so within this process
we have
uh
three concepts here so the first process
here is that when the security guard
verifies your identity
and give you an internal access card
this is
a process of authentication right to
verify that you
are who you say you are
right and then
provide you with this internal access
card and this internal access card
is what we call the security context
right the security context that contains
all of the information about you
so that when you carry the security
contacts
to any of these
buildings
it will then apply certain requirements
to your security context right verify
that your security contact contains
enough
permissions
to satisfy the requirements to enter the
building
okay so in this process is called
authorization right authorization is the
process of verifying that your
identities are
satisfying the requirements of entering
or accessing the
building and similarly in a web
application imagine these sort of
different pages and you have this login
page here that is trying to
like the security guard is asking you to
log in right the process of logging in
which is providing the username password
and verify the username and password
and that is called authentication right
and
authentication also provides you the
security context
right
if it's cookie authentication then it
generates the cookie
right and if it's token authentication
then it generates the token so you have
the cookie either the cookie or the
token or something else that contains
your security context and then the
subsequent
request going into the page different
pages will carry
the
security context
either cookie or token earnteal that
security context expires and then it
will lose your
access to the entire web application
right and
when you access each one of these pages
each page may have different
requirements right so and that's the
authorization comes in right the
authorization process will look at your
security context
and then applies those requirements
toward that security context to see
whether your security contacts actually
satisfies the requirements of accessing
the page
if it does then it will allow you to
access the page if not then it will
return
http 403 era to indicate that although
you have logged in but you don't have
access to this page
right and if you cannot
even log in then will actually return
http 401 saying you're not authenticated
in the previous video i covered
a little bit about security in web
application
in this video i want to cover still on
high level but
i want to provide a little bit more
detail in terms of the flow
so
if we have a user here
trying to access a web page right let's
imagine this login page is already
loaded because
the the user wants to access some
information that requires uh login right
so the user would interact with this
browser to enter the the credentials
right so once the credential is entered
a http request and then it's sent to the
uh to the server right so let's use this
arrow to
represent the http request that is sent
to the server when the server receives
the credentials from the http request
body it's going to then
verify against a user store to make sure
the credentials are
correct why do i draw a database symbol
here that's because the user information
is stored usually in the data store
right so
the credentials need to be verified
against the user's data store
right so this part this step will happen
and if the verification is
completed correctly
that means the credentials are correct
the identity will come back the identity
information will be used to generate the
security context so let's use this
rectangle to represent
this verification process verify
credentials
and then we're going to use this second
rectangle to represent the process of
generating the
security
context
so after the verification
the identities will be pulled into
the web server and
store those identities in the security
context and then serialize that into a
cookie
if you're not very familiar with the
concept of cookie
i just want to add a little bit
information here a cookie can
be considered as a piece of information
that is stored in the header of the http
request and http response right that
information is going to be
carried back and forth
between the browser and the web server
and there is a feature with this piece
of information because in the header you
can contain lots of information
but the cookie is a special type of
information because it can only be
shared within the same
domain
right you cannot
send a request to a different web server
that carries the same cookie because
because there is a security problem all
right let's go back to this
authentication and authorization flow so
let's imagine this is a cookie a normal
cookie authentication which is very
suitable for this
web application
right so then this
uh
serialized cookie will be containing the
http response and then will be returned
back
to the
to the browser the browser will then
redirect the user to
a different page
right and including that redirection
every single subsequent
http request will contain that cookie
right so let's
uh
use another
arrow
to represent one of the subsequent
requests and then this
rectangle
will represent
the
authentication process so you may ask
why this is authentication where this is
already the verification process is
already authentication right so yes
this part
this whole part here
the both of the these rectangles are
part of authentication right
to verify the user is who they say they
are and then generate the security
context
serialize that into a cookie sends that
back to the browser so this is all
authentication process why would we have
this authentication process again well
here we have it in the cookie
right we have the security context in
the cookie
the the web server will have to
deserialize that into the security
context and then
the the web server
will actually know whether the user is
is actually logged in or not right so
this part of deserializing
the security context from the cookie
is also part of authentication right so
so basically in one statement
authentication is the process to know
who you are
okay so
because these security contexts already
stored in the cookie so
in order to know at this step in order
to know who you are it only needs to
decrypt that cookie and deserialize that
cookie
because the cookie is encrypted
so once those happens immediately we
know whether the user is authenticated
or not
so this is still the authentication
process where we decrypt the cookie we
deserialize the cookie to get the
security context and then once we have
the security context
which is actually contained in the http
context object right once we have that
information then we can tell whether the
user is
authorized to access the information
where the page it wants to see right so
that's the second step which is
authorized authorization
okay so authorization will happen right
afterwards
and then and then if everything is okay
then the web server will decide to
return
the proper response that contains the
html and all of the data that the user
requires
from this video i wanted to show you
that
both these steps as well as these
are
part of authentication and then the
authorization process is relatively
simpler from at least conceptual level
in this video i want to quickly cover
the basics of asp.net core including the
middle wire pipeline and the filter
pipeline
i would expect you
have experiences with asp.net core
already but i still want to
uh quickly cover
the the basics just in case you need a
recap so asp.net core is is a platform
for creating web applications that
includes uh web apis as well
so web applications are based on http
request right so you would have uh your
front end and your back-end right so you
have your front-end browser and your
back-end server so the front-end browser
and the back-end server is sending http
request back and forth
right so the http request contains a lot
of information right it can contain
information in the url can contain
information in the http header
as well as body
and other places the request and
response that basically just contains
pieces of information that needs to be
passed back and forth between the
front-end and the back-end right the
browser and the
server
right so let's zoom into
the
server right so let's imagine this is
this part is the server and
because we want to zoom in so we want to
make it bigger so inside this server we
have a place where we need to process
the request right you can have
one function for example to process the
request right here
okay just process
and then
the request is processed
the response is generated and sent back
to the server the the user will see
the html
right so
that's okay but the process itself has
many many steps right like
authentication authorization
exception handlings
logging
rotting
and
validations all those steps need to be
performed right if you couple everything
together that go against a lot of
software design and architecture rules
principles
so in order to process this in a proper
way we can apply some software design
patterns and one of the software design
patterns is this is so called the chain
of responsibilities
right so then we would have
many functions instead of one function
we can have many functions here right
let's say just call it function one
function three
and function n
all right so all of these can be
connected together so what this
connection means is that this message
will be handed
to the function for the first function
and the first function will process it
do something to that message right kind
of mutate that message
and then pass that message to the second
one to process the message and change
that message
right and then pass on to the last one
and then return that message back still
process it afterwards still process it
and pass it all the way and then
generate the final http response and
send that back to the browser
and by the way the message that i'm
referring to is the http context object
that encapsulate both the http request
and the http response
so this is uh what we call the
middleware pipeline
right this middlewire pipeline
it kind of separates
it kind of does the separation of
concerns each middleware in the pipeline
takes different responsibilities
but usually the last one that are
responsible to process the the business
logic here has its own
middle has its own pipeline
right because
these are for
cross cutting concerns like exception
handlings
logins
right authentication authorization um
partially partially authorization and
then here
according to each different request we
process them differently and therefore
uh we should have another pipeline that
uh will
according to the different requests will
process it differently right the the
second pipeline here are not
handling cross-cutting concerns but
handling specific concerns for
the specific
request
so you would have
different filters here instead of
different
middlewares there right so these
functions are basically middlewares
right
so so here then you would have filter
one
filter two i'm not writing
it anymore
right filter three for example so your
request i mean your message will be
also goes going through all of these
so here i want to emphasize this may not
go in one by one i may go through the
first one and then go around
and then going back may not go through
each one of them it may go around
whereas in middleware it will go
like that but anyway this
filter pipeline has many filters
connected together
and these are for handling specific
requests whereas these are for handling
crosscutting concerns
so this is
the the basics of asp.net core right and
once i go into coding very very quickly
in in the next few videos i will share
coding and
these concepts are important to know
before that
another very important concept to
understand before i actually start
coding and show you how uh security
identity actually works within asp.net
core is this security context
okay so what is actually the security
contact the security context contains
all the information
that the user has for security purpose
that includes the user information
itself username
and all of the other type of user
information like email addresses
right
those informations are actually
encapsulated within one single
object that is called claims principle
in asp.net core
we're using claims principle so that's
why i mentioned claims principle but
it's actually we can say that on a
conceptual level
we have a principal object that
represents this security context of the
user right basically you can consider
this is the user
right
and the principle contains
one or many
identities of the user why there can be
many type of identities
i think i have explained in the first
video that you know one person can have
many type of identities right you can
for example
you can be a student and you have a
student card you can be an employee and
you have an employee card and you can
have your driver's license and you can
have the access card to your apartment
building so all of these
are a form of identity and then the next
level is the next level is claims so
one
identity
then can contain many
claims
what are claims
claims are basically a key value pair
that carries your information for
example on your driver's license for
example this this identity is your
is your driver's license identity right
driver's license
and
you can see that on drivers license
there is your name
right for example my name and then you
may have your
uh your birthday right whatever your
birthday is and then you could have your
uh your height
whether you need to wear
glasses where you're driving
driver's license also contains my eye
color and as well as my address
all right so all of these are claims but
these are just examples of claims of
course
this
one claim is just one key and pair
one key pair right so
if you want driver's license to contain
all of these
then it would be like this right so
these are the relationships between
principles
identities and claims
again one the principle represents
the logged in user it can has all of the
information that login user has
and then the principal can have
many identities usually we have just one
identity
which is the default identity and then
one identity can have many claims
which carries all of the user
information and then eventually when
we're doing authorization we can use
these claims
we can
apply those requirements on each
page or resource in our web server
those requirements that requires certain
claims to be present in order to gain
access to the resource
let's jump right into video studio and
start digging deep under the hood to
understand spdin core security
so i'm using video studio 2019 community
edition and i'm about to create a
spd.net core web application
right you can come over here and do
web
app
okay search web app and then you can see
asp.org web application click on next
and so you basically enter your
locations project name and solution name
and then click on create
and what we are going to create is a
speedometer quarter web app so this is
going to be the
reason pages application it's not going
to be model view controller because
right now microsoft considers the
reserve pages solution is the primary
solution that's why in this course i'm
using the razer pages
solution
so then
without creating any authentication
let's click on the create and then we
can start from scratch
without using any default setup for
authentication so so that we can
understand the security the identity
aspect of asp.net core completely so i'm
clicking on the
create button so now we have the
application created this is the
intermediate course i'm now going to go
about and
show you
which file is what and how they all work
together i'm going to come to this
diagram and
we'll follow this diagram back and forth
along these lines so we can investigate
each and every single step so first of
all
we are
we don't have a login page right but we
do have other pages where we're going to
send requests and receive a response so
let's examine this
this part first because this part
carries all of our security context so
this is the first part we're going to
examine so we have a index page
right and we don't have any uh
protection on the page so we should be
able to just run without any problems
all right so this page is loaded but
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
come over here and i'm going to set a
breakpoint and then i'm going back to
the page i'm going to refresh the page
now my breakpoint is triggered
so what i'm going to do is
i'm going to add something to look at
i'm going to examine the
information
under the page model of the razer pages
which contains the data construct for
razer pages which is pretty similar to
mvc still construct
and if we say base dot and we can see
all of the data construction one of them
is
user and if you look cl uh closely you
can see that this is the claims
principle which is the security context
that i talked about in the previous
video the
security context is under the user right
because it is the user principle so then
what is under there
and you can see that the principles can
contain
a list of identities
currently it only has one
and this is the primary identity this
identity is the primary identity which
is sort of like uh in the first video
when i talked about when you go into the
military
facility
as a person you have many type of
identities you have your driver's
license you can have your employee card
you can have your student card you can
have everything you can even have a you
can have a library card right
but uh the identity that is the primary
identity supposed to be the one that is
provided to you by the military right so
this identity
is our primary identity that our asp.net
core currently is working with
right so if we
go to
that and we do dot identity
and then
we can see that
it has
different informations here and the main
information is claims which doesn't have
anything
and the reason is that this current
identity is a anonymous identity you can
see that this is authenticated member
it's currently false why is it anonymous
identity because i haven't logged in yet
i didn't touch any login page in fact we
don't have a login page so in this case
we're not we're actually uh
logging in quote and quote
to this web application without any
identity and this
is still considered as a identity and
this identity is the anonymous identity
and that's why the is authenticated is
false
so in other words whether you're logged
in or not logged in once the http
request goes into sb.cor asp.net core
creates
the the primary identity for you right
regardless whether you're logged in or
not and if you're logged in then it will
contain all of your security contacts
right if it doesn't log in it will
contain a anonymous identity which is
still a security context but it's an
anonymous one so this is the concept i
would like you to understand that
regardless whether you're logged in or
not you have a security context you have
a primary identity
under your security context
since in the last video we have learned
about the anonymous identity inside the
http context object in this video we're
going to create a login page so that we
can have an actual login identity
instead of anonymous one so let's jump
into video studio and continue from what
we have created from the previous video
so since this is a resource page
solution we are going to create a
subfolder under here
and let's call it
account
and then we're going to create
a login page so we are not going to
scout fold from
identity framework inside speed.net core
we're going to create our own login page
and then we can learn about what exactly
is happening under the hood instead of
just using the scope folding okay let's
create a
empty reader page and let's call it
login all right so we have the the
cshtml page here
and then we have this page behind here
okay so this is uh actually based on mvc
framework
but it gives you a
mvvm field right it's instead of mvc it
gives you mvpm feel so
uh because of that the first thing we
need to create is a it's a model that
you can use to communicate between the
front and the back right and let's call
that model
a credential model
okay so we haven't created yet
but that's okay we can uh
create right now and let's just call it
credential
okay so this is not created and that's
fine we're going to create it right
under here and we can create a public
class
and let's call it credential
and we are going to have
a
username
and of course a password
all right so this
class will be used as a model to
communicate between the front and the
back
right the reader pages and the the page
model here
and of course we can add some validation
here
and this one we can make a required
field
and of course here we're going to do
control dot to import the namespace
and same over here we're going to
make it required and make this a
password data type
and then what we need to do is we're
going to make this a bind property
so that it gives you a feeling of
two-way data binding right so
with this property set up we can go to
the and then we can just enter the html
that we want to use okay so by default
solution comes with bootstrap in the
layout.c as html you can see the
bootstrap is here
so we can enter some bootstrap classes
okay so this is going to be a container
and
we want to have a border so that it
looks
better right and then uh we're gonna
add a little bit of padding right so we
have a div here and then
uh we need a form
right and this is going to be
a post
form
allowing you to post we're gonna have
uh two rows right and this is going to
be a form group
uh
and this is
row number one and then inside the row
we have two columns
right the first column is for the label
the second one is going to be for let's
change it to five
so right this one is a narrower column
and this is a wider column right so this
is going to be for the label
so before we do that we can uh
well let's
enter
a label here
and this is going to be bond to that
credential
to this credential field
okay so we're going to call this so this
should be bound to that and that's this
is the way we do it with tag helper
and then
we'll do input and this is going to be a
text for sure
and
to be bound to
the
the same field
right so this is the actual binding but
this one gives you the the label name
and then we're going to copy this and of
course this one
is going to be
button to the password field
and the input
is also bound to the password field so
let's run it and see let me do ctrl f5
okay
so in order to navigate to it in reader
pages it's based on
folder by default so we don't have to
specify attribute in order to
to uh
navigate to it so we're just basically
doing the folder name right and then the
page name
so we have it and
i
don't like the label to be too big so
let's actually change that
to
instead of three let's change that to
two
and
and thus
we'll add a
form control to make it look better same
as this forgot to add the class
the css class
okay going over here i'm going to do a
refresh
okay so apparently we need a submit
button and for that we are
basically just doing this and deleting
this
and i'm going to keep my input button
here so this is going to be a submit
button
okay and then
this is going to be a primary
button
and then the label is logging all right
so let's refresh the page
okay so we have a login button here if i
click on this button
it does a post back you can see it does
a postback
so this is not exactly what we want
right because
you have to really enter your username
password
this is not doing the validation we need
to make sure that it validates right and
in reader pages to do that it's very
simple first on the top within the form
we're going to add a
div the class would be
gender
right and then it's going to be for
validation all right we're going to use
tag helper validation summary
and then we'll say model only okay so
this is going to be validating our model
which is the credential field and then
for each field
right we are going to add a span
and
again we're going to say
text standard for the css class
and it's validation
it's going to be validating this field
okay so you can see
with the tag helper both the
model binding as well as validation is
very
simple
the page and then now you can see that
the validation is displayed let's say
our username is admin and
our password is going to be password
of course you can see this this field is
not playing very nicely it's showing my
password
so we need to fix that problem and we
come back to this login.cs
html and we're going to change this
instead of text so this part is has to
be a password so you're going to refresh
this page
and then
password is password now it's doing
incorrectly all right so if once we
click on this
this credentials has to be sent to to
here to be bought here
so but then how do we receive the
postback event and that's when we are
doing
in
uh on post okay so this is by convention
so let's do a debug here
we're gonna run debug and then we
navigate to our login page so if type in
our password
and then
going over here if we watch this dot
credential
we can see that the username and
password is actually
received so this is you know two-way
data binding
a feeling of two-way data binding at
least although i only demonstrated the
one-way data binding which is binding
from the ui
to our page behind
right so we can do the other i can
although it doesn't make sense but
we can definitely
do the other one which is uh so we're
gonna have the credential we're gonna
initialize the credential
okay and then we can have the at least
we can populate
the
the username
and then when we're doing this
right
so when the page is requested the login
page is requested this get handler is
going to be executed when it's post back
this post handler is going to be
executed so when
this get handler is executed we populate
our model and then this information will
be used inside the view here okay so
let's let's run that and see
that is really a feeling of two-way data
binding it's really a feeling of mvvm
although this is all based on mvc i know
this is kind of outside the security
course
since you should have already known this
but
razer pages haven't been around for too
long that's why i wanted to cover it
just a little bit so you can see that
the
admin
is populated here so this is from our
page model
to the ui
and then
we set a breakpoint here
so once we submit the form
then we would receive our credential
from the ui
to the page model
right so this is a two-way data binding
and of course we don't need
the username to be pre-populated and
another thing is this username is not
displayed correctly it's displayed as
one word so when we display it
we want it to be displayed
as separate word so we can provide that
over here
okay so once we have that then we
refresh the page and we can see that the
username is separated so next step is
that we need to
verify the credentials inside post and
then we need to generate the security
context which is the claims principle so
we'll do that in the next video
now that we have implemented a login
page and we have also covered where the
security context is stored we're ready
to implement the verifications
credentials as well as generating the
security context so let's jump into
video studio and start implementing
those logic so first of all we need to
make sure that we do have our
credentials and for that we need to
check our model state to see whether
it's valid or not
and if it's not valid
we're going to return
and then next we want to verify the
credentials
and we are not going to connect to the
database we're not interested in that
we're interested in the security aspect
of that
so that's why
we're just hardcoding
the verification process here so i want
to make sure that username is admin
and the password
is password so as long as we have these
two
match
the username and password
then
we're okay next step
right so
here we verify
the credential
right and then the second step here we
are
creating the security context
and if we go back to our diagram that we
drew before we will need to create a
bunch of claims and then we add to the
identity
we only need one identity which is the
primary identity once we have the
primary identity we add it to the claims
principle and
we are done with creating the security
context right so for that
we'll all instantiate a list of claims
i'm doing ctrl dot to import
the namespace here
and then of course we are going to add
let's add
some claims here
right so
we're gonna have a
a name
and let's call just admin
and perhaps we'll add another one
we'll add another claim
and let's see what options do we have
here
we do we have an email yeah we have an
email let's say
i mean at
my website.com
right that's good enough now that we
have the claims
you know we we we have mentioned the
claims are just uh
a pair of attributes right
uh and with that we we need to add those
claims
to a identity so now we need to declare
and instantiate
the uh identity and
what we need is a claims identity
which we can add claims to it
and then here what we want to have is
the authentication type
the authentication type let's give it a
name and then i'm going to talk about
this later
right so
let's
we're gonna use cookie authentication
which is the typical type of
authentication for a login page
right let's call it my cookie
uh
like my cookie authentication
okay
and give it you can give it whatever
name you want
so once we have the identity
uh then what we need is a claims
principle i'm going to instantiate that
and
it can be empty but you can also
provide a primary identity you can also
provide this
primary identity here
so now we have this security context
within the claims principle right we
have learned that
the
principle
contains the security context
now what we need to do we can see that
we generate the security context but
then
next step is we need to
encrypt and serialize the
security context and then it can go into
the cookie right
but we don't need to do that ourselves
we can use the http context object
it has a it has a sign
in async method here
which is a extension method you can see
it's a it's extension method it comes
from
the spd.net core http namespace
right so we can do that
and
here
we also want to specify
the
authentication scheme which is
the authentication type and we want this
authentication type to be exactly the
same as this one
right and then here we can provide the
principle that's the second parameter
all right so i'm going to put in the
claims principle here since this is
async right so we need to await it and
because of that
what we need to do is i'll change this
to
a
a task and it has to be async task and
because of that we'll also
make this one
async so this one is supposed to what it
does is that it's going to
serialize the claims principle into a
string and then encrypt that string save
that as a cookie in the http context
right into the cookie inside gtp context
object
and if everything is
good then we're going to redirect we're
going to redirect to a page so let's
just redirect to the index page
you can see that this redirect to page
it actually returns the redirect to page
result
so because of that we are going to
instead of
making this a void
we're going to make it return i action
result
of course here what we can do here we
have to fix it we can return the the
page result here
so what's going to happen here is that
it's going to
basically return
the view
right so this one is going to find the
index field and return the index field
right we we return the page result we're
returning the login.cs
html right which is the cshtml object
and if the uh the verification failed
then it will fall out of this branch
and again we're going to return a page
okay
so let's build this solution and then
let's run it right so because we did not
configure uh authorization that's why i
did not
redirect us to the login page directly
but we can go to the login page
right and then we can type in
the password
and if i type in something that is wrong
so it will return directly back to the
login page which is
this one right but if i
input the correct password
then
watch what happens
it throws exception
so let's look look into this exception
see it says that no sign in
authentication handlers are registered
did you forget to call the ad
authentication at cookie it tells you
exactly what you need to do here
but before we actually do this
let's try to understand what is actually
happening here where it says that on
this line
that something is is wrong
so what exactly is is wrong here right
let's look at read this error message
again it says there's no sign in
authentication handlers
authentication handlers so this is the
keyword authentication handlers
okay
so what is actually happening is that
this http contact sign in async under
the hood it uses the authentication
handler which is provided
to
this
uh through the eye authentication
service interface
okay so let's let's take a look at the
eye authentication service interface
see this interface contains the
abstraction of several methods
right
there is this sign async which is
exactly
uh the
the one that we're missing right it
contains sign out uh challenge for bid
and authenticate so these
are the abstractions of the
authentication handlers
right so what is complaining here is
that the http contacts.signing async is
trying to use the eye authentication
service interface but it cannot find any
concrete implementation of that
interface so we are missing no we don't
have the
handlers here
and it asks you to inject
right so this is the dependency
injection under the configure services
right it asks you to inject the
implementation of those handlers let's
take a step back and see what is
actually happening here as from the
design pattern point of view okay so
let's see this uh let's use this printf
in the c language for example right
usually this printf will
print to to the console to your screen
so this is the output the print div will
output to the console but if you
use different libraries it can go to the
console right it can also
go to
let's say a printer okay it can go to
any other i o devices
what is actually happening under the
hood is that the printf is not talking
to
these devices directly
what is actually talking to is a
abstraction of the the io devices in c
plus plus this would be a abstract class
so these drivers implement the
abstraction
and then as long as you import
the libraries of the corresponding
drivers then you are able to print to a
console or printer or other devices
right so what this print app is really
talking to is this abstraction so this
kind of design pattern this kind of
design pattern is is basically uh it's
everywhere
it's typically when you have uh some io
devices you don't want to
lock your
library to a particular
output device
right you don't want to for example you
don't want to log
your output to just sql server database
right by logging to a
specific sql server database library
you want to talk to a interface
and then develop all of these as plugins
so in our case it's the same situation
here we are having a
a bunch of authentication and
authorization
in this case we're talking about
authentication right we're having some
requirements for authentication and it
needs to
uh to serialize the information right
the security context
to either a cookie or token or something
else they are kind of like a i o
thing it's outside the application
boundary it's under the http protocol
right so
the security context can be stored or
can be serialized to either a cookie or
token or something else you don't want
to lock yourself to just cookie or just
a token like this right you don't want
to directly talk to it so what you
actually want to do is you want to do a
similar thing okay so inside your
application okay so let's use this uh
this square or rectangle as a boundary
for your application inside it you want
to talk to a abstraction and this is the
i
authentication
service this interface in c sharp
it contains the abstraction of of all of
your needs for authentication
right so your actual authentication
will just talk to this abstraction and
then the cookies or tokens the different
authentication handlers as long as it
implements this authentication service
then the only thing as a developer what
you need to do is to
tell the asp.net core
that
either you want a cookie authentication
handler to be injected or a token
authentication handler to be injected
or
both
okay or both
and that's where the authentication
scheme name or the authentication type
name come into play
right that that name comes into play
because it can be
this or this very cookie or token or
both
because there can be multiple
authentication handlers that implements
the eye authentication service
we want to give them different names so
that we can distinguish where asp.net
core can distinguish which is which we
can use the name to group the the cookie
the
security context which is the principal
identities
and the authentication handler itself
together and that's why we need to
specify the name everywhere
and what is that name
that is the authentication scheme or the
authentication type
which you have seen when i was
implementing it so let's jump into video
studio and see how we implement
these
right and it's actually very clear here
it's actually telling you you need to
add authentication
you need to do this
so let's copy this
and let's stop debugging and let's go
into our startup
where we can find this server configure
services services this is where we want
to inject
our authentication handler so over here
uh what we want to do is i'm going to
paste this over here right
so we're going to do this services.add
so basically we're adding services to a
collection you can see this is a service
collection interface here right we're
adding this authentication
handler to the to the service collection
and this ad cookie is adding the cookie
authentication handler right this means
that
all of the implementations first
encrypting and serializing the security
contacts will be injected into
asp.net core
by just calling this extension method
which is um
implemented by a speedometer core
right so we don't have to specifically
implement how does encryption decryption
uh serializing destroyizing works we
just need to add this cookie
authentication handler all we have to be
really taken care of is to give it a
name
right we can give our own name we can
yeah it's just a string right so
and then here let's take a look at the
the second parameter here
which is
the options so we want to
also
make sure we configure
our options correctly here and and in
here there's there's a lot of different
things we can configure right but
at this moment the most important thing
is that we need to configure our cookie
and especially our cookie name we want
this to be just like that
so this specifies the cookie name
which is
the most important aspect in in the
cookie authentication by doing so
you specify target of the serialization
and asp.net core knows which cookie
contains the authentication security
context
okay so let's
at this moment only configure the cookie
name here and then we can see that we
have been very careful of
using the same name
right in the cookie name
in the authentication scheme name
as well as in the
identity associate this cookie name with
identity and provide this cookie or the
authentication scheme name to the sign
where they are all the same
name so that we can kind of logically
group them together
of course the best practice here is to
declare a constant
right i'm not going to do that when we
actually implement a solution we should
actually declare
a constant for this in case we have some
tab typos all right so let's run the
solution again
okay i'm going to
bring up the developer tool right
by pressing f12 and then i'm going to go
to
right clicking on this double arrow and
then i go to applications
i want to look at the cookies right so
get go under cookies
right open this up and then go into this
domain right cookies are always
associated with specific domains so
we are looking at this domain so that's
why we have to go enter this domain and
we can see that we don't have my cookie
us
the cookie name we only have this by
default we have this we have this
anti-forgery uh a cookie here
right so we don't have our cookie yet
but let's watch what's happening here so
that's going to provide
the correct username and
password
and then let's watch whether we're going
to have a cookie or not
all right
so you can see that we have a cookie
right we have a cookie so this is all
encrypted
right and serialized so this contains
our uh security context which is the
claims principle but we can't see
anything because it's really uh
encrypted within this domain and where
does the cookie come from that comes
from
here so this http contact sign async
is triggered and it talks to the i
authentication service interface
and who has implemented that interface
that what we have chosen to inject into
our asp.net core by calling at cookie so
this cookie authentication handler
is injected and we have configured to
take this
authentication scheme name
right and we made sure we're using the
same authentication scheme name we we
grouped them all together
and so that when we trigger this method
it uses the cookie authentication
handler that we have injected into
asp.net core taking this name and
finally we can see that claim principle
security context is created over here
taking
the
cookie name okay so let's recap what we
have done today is
we
input username and password we
implemented this uh
verification process and we implemented
the generating process right we generate
the security context within the claims
claims principle
we injected the authentication the
cookie authentication handlers
right and we successfully created the
cookie so the cookie is now sent back
to the browser we saw that in the in the
browser developer tool
so in the next video we are going to
follow this line to see
whether
we have the cookie deserialized and
decrypted
i'll see you in the next one
so in the previous video we verified the
credential here
and then we generated the security
context serialized the security context
into a cookie and send that cookie back
to the browser right we could see the
cookie in the browser developer tool and
it looks like this
it is encrypted in this video let's
follow this arrow to look into what this
authentication does and how it does it
so i'm already from the login page
redirected back to the index page right
so let's set a breakpoint at the get
handler of the index page okay so let's
set a breakpoint right here
and then we'll see what happens i'm
going to refresh the page and then this
is triggered so let's watch what do we
have for the user and we can see that we
have
one identity
which is that's claims for identity
unfortunately
it is still
a anonymous identity
but we have already logged in we have
successfully generated the cookie why on
earth this primary identity is still a
anonymous identity let's go back to our
diagrams right over here
and we'll see that what is really going
on here okay so the browser does have
the cookie
and then when the brother sent another
request to the index page
right the cookie is definitely sent to
the server
right
but the fact that
we still see anonymous identity it means
the server didn't look at the cookie so
what is responsible to look at the
cookie okay so that's uh related to the
the middleware
so this is the this is the browser right
so the browser sends request
into asb.net core
what is responsible for precising the
request it's those middlewares that are
hooked together right and the request is
actually encapsulated in one object
which is the http context object right
that is the object we were looking at
when we were checking we were watching
here so we were watching this a base
that a base dot user right but it's
actually from the http
context so if we do http context we
would see
it would see the same thing
okay
and this user would also have
the primary identity and still
is unauthenticated
is false right so we know that along
these lines the request actually is
within the http context so there's got
to be a
middleware who's uh going to look into
the http header within the http context
and then populate
the security context
with the corresponding values so and
that middleware is our authentication
middleware
okay so when the authentication
middleware is looking at the http
request
within the http context
it should be able to
see
the header that contains the cookie and
then it will interpret that cookie and
after the processing it will populate
the
security context right the claims
principle with the values translated
from the cookie so that's the job for
the authentication middleware to do the
reason why the primary identity still is
still the anonymous identity and that's
because we didn't set up our
authentication middleware right the
authentication middleware is missing
that's why
it's still the anonymous one
so now what we need to do is very simple
we just need to insert
the authentication middleware in the
pipeline and to do that let's go to our
startup.cs file let's stop our debugging
and then we go to configure method
and over here
uh
above this authorization model need to
say use authentication right so this
basically inserted the authentication
middleware which is responsible to
call the authentication handler right so
if we look at our high authentication
service interface
we can see that this authenticate async
right we can see this is
the one
right so authenticate for the specific
authentication so this one is going to
be called and this method is going to be
called and is supposed to
uh be able to translate all of the
cookie into the
security context the claims principle
all right so let's see
once we added this uh what is going to
happen so everything that this up this
middleware needs is already injected
with these four lines of code okay so
this uh
we have injected the authentication
service which contains the cookie
authentication handlers
and that's why it's able to
convert the cookie into our claims
principle because we have already
injected
our cookie authentication service right
the cookie agent authentication handlers
all right so let's run a debug again and
see whether it's going to work this time
okay so
let's go to our login page okay we
haven't set up our
authorization yet so i have to manually
go to our login page
okay so
uh
we have logged in
and then
if we
refresh that page
and then we watch
the uh this one we could see the primary
identity and then we notice that this is
a dedicated property it's still false
so what is going on we have already put
the middleware there why is not
interpreting the cookie correctly
well we know that what is actually
interpreting the cookie is the
authentication handler or the service
that we injected into our pipeline
right
and that is this cookie authentication
service that we have already did
but we also know that
there could be multiple authentication
service that are injected right you can
use
multiple different cookies
authentication handler with different
names you can have cookie you can have
token
although we have inserted the middleware
in the pipeline it does not know
which scheme
you want to use right the scheme name
it provides a logical grouping that
groups your authentication handlers
your identities
your claims principles all together
right you have to tell the middleware
which scheme
you are trying to use so that
the middleware is able to locate
which
authentication service you are trying to
use to do the authentication
all right so the way to do that is
actually pretty simple so we have to
provide a authentication scheme name in
here to tell the authentication
middleware which authentication scheme
we wanted to use to do the
authentication so it's the same name as
the authentication service it's my
cookie boss
so let's give that a try
all right so we input our password
and then now we
arrive at our
breakpoint again
you can see the base that user contains
that identity and this time
the
identity
is authenticated and we can also see the
claims that we added over here
which
is you know the name is admin
and
the email address is admin mywebsite.com
all right finally we're able to
translate the cookie
into our security context
having said all of this uh it's actually
really simple right the reason why i
included so many details here is to
really try to make you understand
exactly what is happening here that we
need a middleware in order to do the
authentication in the middleware uses
the injected
cookie authentication handler
but because they're multiple different
there could be multiple different
authentication handlers you have to
specify
which is the one that should be used in
the middleware
right by specifying the name here right
you can add multiple
of these but
there can be only one that is used to do
the authentication and you just have to
specify the name
in this case we only have one
right so
all of these names are the same
including the name
in here
right for the identities
and for sending the cookie
all right so that's everything in this
video
i'll see you in the next one
in this video let's learn about how
authorization works in the asp.net core
so if you have a browser here and you
input a url in the browser
and you want to access a certain
endpoint or a certain page on the server
so let's say we have page
one page two page three and page four
different pages may have different
requirements for accessing the page
right for example page one could be
allowing anonymous users to access
whereas page two
could be a admin only page and maybe
page three will only allow people from
the hr department and page
may be looking at
you know you have to be
a
admin
and also you have to from the hr
department right it's a combination of
these two and maybe you have page five
where you have a for example a casino
online casino page
where you have to be older than 18 years
old okay so there's all different kinds
of requirements on different pages or
different endpoints we're talking about
web api so these requirements have to be
satisfied in order for the user
to access these pages
right we know that when a request is
sent to
sp9 core server
it goes through a pipeline after it goes
through the authentication middleware we
know the security context which contains
the identity of the user
and identity contains a set of claims
right and it's going to tell us whether
the user is or the main user
which department the user comes from
what what is the age of the user
so all of the information are contained
in the claims
and
of course before
the authentication
middleware comes in this
rotting middleware that tells us which
endpoint it's trying to
navigate to and then the authentication
middleware will be able to deserialize
the cookie
into our security contact the claims
principles identities as well as
claims
right
then at this point we know for example
we're trying to hit page two who's going
to check the requirement that's
the authorization
middleware
okay so the authorization middleware is
the middleware that will look at
the
[Music]
the claims from the user
and then look at the requirements from
the page and then compare them and make
sure that claims satisfy the requirement
and if that's the case then it will
allow
the user to access the page
otherwise it will return http 4 3
which is a challenge right but you don't
have the permission to access the page
although you're logged in so that's how
authorization works on higher level
but the question is what are those
requirements in asp.net core we actually
have requirement classes and then we can
group different requirements together
form a policy so
we would have a policy
and one policy can have one or many
requirements let's use two for example
so we can define these policies in the
configure services method
within the
startup.cs file which i'll show you
later
right we can define these policies and
then we can apply these policies by
using the authorized attribute on the
appropriate pages
which i'll also demonstrate later in the
next video in this video i just want to
give you an overview of the architecture
of how authorization works right so we
can define a policy which contains bunch
of requirements so these requirements
are pretty simple the presence
of the admin claim is there then we're
okay right if the department claim has a
hr value then we allow the user to
access page three right and this is
basically a simple combination of two
claims as long as they are there
then we allow access to it but then it
comes to this uh there is a comparison
how does the
the authorization middleware be able to
handle this type of requirement checking
well
we have to create custom requirement
ourselves and we have to implement
the logic of handling those requirements
as a matter of fact in asp.net core for
each requirement
there has to be a corresponding
authorization handler to handle those
requirements
right so basically
the authorization middleware
uses
something that is called high
authorization
service
just like the authentication middleware
uses the eye authentication service
right and then the the implementation of
the searches authorization service will
look through all of the requirements
right and find corresponding handlers to
handle each requirement
actually each requirement
must have a corresponding handler
for checking the presence of the claims
there's generic ones to do the job but
if you come up with a particular
requirement that needs particular logic
then you have to implement your own
requirement let's say requirement one is
a specific contains a specific logic you
have to implement that authentication
handler yourself by creating a class and
derive that class from authorization
handler to handle
this requirement right so in this case
the policy
is applied to a certain page right which
contains a
custom requirement requirement one and
then we have a requirement one
authorization handler to check the
requirement
and then the authorization service will
be invoked by the authorization
middleware and this completes the
authorization requirement checking
once it's complete
it's going to either grant you the
access to the page
or deny
you from accessing the page
just to recap
after
writing an authorization we know which
end point we're trying to hit like which
page we're trying to hit and we have all
of the claims
and then the authorization
middleware
will be able to check
what is the requirement a uses
authorization service
requirement handler in order to check
whether the logging user satisfies the
requirement
for this endpoint because it has the
identity of the login user it has all
the claims of the user then the
authorization handler will be able to
look at the claims and the requirement
and then compare them and implement any
type of logic that it needs to right the
generic authorization handlers is enough
to handle those simple scenarios where
you just say i want this user to be
admin
right there's no logic just checking the
presence of
the
claim or checking the value of the claim
of a certain claim so those ones can be
handled by generic
authorization handler
but for specific ones with specific
logics you can implement a handler
yourself
and this is the whole flow
and architecture of authorization i hope
it helps
and if you have any questions don't
hesitate to ask if not
i'll see you in the next video
where we're gonna implement
authorization
in this video we're going to learn about
how to implement authorization in the
asp.net core
so we have gone through this diagram in
the previous video and we know that the
first step we need to do is to apply
a requirement
the simplest requirement we can apply to
a page
is to deny anonymous users and to do
that it's very simple
let's go to a page in our case we have a
index page
okay and we can deny anonymous access on
the index page and we can just simply go
to the page behind here and then we go
to the class we decorate it with the
authorized
attribute which simply denies anonymous
identity
so i'm going to
import the namespace and now let's see
what's going to happen if
we run
our application so of course the first
page is trying to hit is the index page
but because our index page is protected
right so
it automatically redirects us to account
logging the login page right with the
return url to be nothing it's empty
if you happen to see the next page it
could mean that you had your cookie here
that you didn't clear the cookie right
because we haven't implemented the sign
out
functionality and if you didn't close
your browser so your browser session
will still
keep that cookie inside the
the browser
so once you clear the cookie you should
be able to see your login page
but what happens is really we have our
authorization middleware after the
rotting it is seeing that you try to hit
a
page that needs
identities but it's not there so it
returns a http 401 challenge
registration challenge which
automatically redirected you to login
page the reason why it knows where your
login page is is that by default the
login page is supposed to be placed in
the account folder and supposed to be
called login right the page is supposed
to be called login
it happens to be the case that we
followed the convention right so if we
change just temporarily we change the
folder to account one and then if we run
our application again let's see what
happens
now it's trying to still look for
the login page but then it says h2v4
okay so to
explicitly specify where your login page
is
you need to go to
your startup.cs and then go under the
uh the configure
services here
and inside the cookie authentication
handler here we can specify where the
login page is right so we can say login
path
right so in here we can just specify
account
and then login
well we can specify account one because
we apply local one right if we
specify this here
right and just pay attention that here
uh we haven't even logged in yet so so
this is still part of authentication
that's why we're configuring
authentication we're not configuring
authorization yet
all right so let's run the application
again
and then this time it successfully
located the login page under account one
right so let's change it back to account
and let's change this
to the folder back to account
and that
is supposed to work all right so let's
input our username and password
and now we successfully accessed our
index page right our welcome page and
from our developer tool we can see the
cookie is present now okay so let's
delete this cookie for now
and then close this developer tool just
close the window going back to our code
the next thing i want to show you is
that placing the attribute right the
requirement on the page or on any
endpoint
requires the middleware to be present
right so because if you place a
requirement there and there's no
middleware and nothing is dependency
injected
then it's not going to do anything and
it's actually going to throw an error so
let's see what happens there so because
we already have the authorization
middleware placed
right over here right so if we comment
this out
and then we run it let's see what
happens now now we can see it throws an
error and the error is very descriptive
it says that this endpoint index
contains authorization metadata
but a middleware was not found that
supports authorization
right and then it tells you what to do
well you can see that microsoft has come
up with really nice really detailed
error messages for developer to code
many years ago it is in this case
anyways this is what i want to show you
that
if you decorate a endpoint
with your requirement you have to
specify the authorization all right so
next let's add another page here
and then let's call this page the hr
department
right so this is going to be the hr
department landing page
and we're going to create a reader page
which is amt1
and then let's call it
human resource
and let's add some style and let's use
the same styling and copy and paste that
over to our human resource
cshtml
page
over here and then
so this is
we're going to change the title here to
human
resource and delete this learn about
here
we need to specify a policy that
requires the
department claim
to see whether the department is hr and
then
we assign this requirement to the policy
and then we apply this policy
to
the page so in order to specify the
requirement and group the requirements
into
the policy
we need to configure authorization
okay and
and you know where we should go we
should go to startup.cs and then go
under configure version server configure
services here this one dependency inject
a lot of
services for authentication purpose
of course we have another one that is
similar to this
which is add authorization right so
we'll dependency inject services
as well as figuring authorization over
here and what we can do with the options
here
is that we can add a policy okay and
then we can give the policy a name so
this one is uh
let's call it must
belong
to
hr
department
so this is the policy name and then you
can see that we need to specify how this
policy works
was action delegate right and for that
we can just use
lambda expressions or and then we can
say policy dot require
and we're gonna require claim the claim
type is department
and the value has to be
hr
we have added our first policy here we
added this
claim
to this policy
right and now we can apply this policy
on our
human resource page and we can go over
here
and we can apply this again it's the
same attribute authorize attribute
do control dot to import namespace
and over here we can say
policy
equals this policy name
so now what we are saying is that
the user must have a
claim that satisfies this policy and
what is the policy is really asking for
is very simple it requires the
department
claims value to be hr
but at this moment
if we go to our login page right we
created our claim to only have
the name and email we don't have a
department claim yet so at this moment
if i do control f5
it's going to build the application and
it's going to run the application and
then we'll see what happens
right first of all i got a login and
then i'm going to insert
my password over here
okay so no problem accessing the index
page
but if we're trying to access our hr
our human resource page i'm going to hit
enter it's going to tell me access
denied you see the access denied and
it's trying to say that hey the access
denied page is not there
right so
you can see that again this is
uh by default
the access denied page supposed to be
under the account page
and
if we were to specify where the access
denied page is
we're again going back to startup.cs
then you can see we specify the login
page right and then we can specify the
access denied page
right over here
okay so we can explicitly specify this
and then we can just copy this name and
then we just add another reader page
click on add specify the name as access
denied coming over here and again we're
gonna say
our title is access denied
and then here we're going to say
you don't have you don't have access
to the page
you are looking for so with this simple
change if we access our human resource
page again it redirected us to the
access denied page right this looks a
little bit better than before so then
how do we gain access
to our human resource page the answer is
pretty simple we go to our login page
and then here we are going to add
another claim here we're going to add
a
claim
right this is the type
and then the value
let's say hr and this has to be exactly
the same as where we configured on the
startup.cs here
we're going to say the type name is
department
right and the value is hr
and so here
the claim
claim type name is department and the
value is hr so which does change again
let's run it
once again okay so you can see that i am
logged in already because i didn't close
my all of my browsers so
the cookie is still inside here
right so this is the old cookie it
doesn't have the new
uh
the new claims so i have to delete this
and if in this case
at this moment if i refresh it takes me
to the login page
where i'm going to re-authenticate
and then i'm going to click on the login
page
now my cookie regenerated this cookie
will contain the new claim
so now let's try to access
our human resource page you see now we
have access to our human resource page
so this is a simple
uh condition here right we're just
checking
whether or not
our cookie contains this particular
claim okay what if we want to check a
presence of a certain claim
again in a simple case for that we are
going to
create a let's say let's
create a control panel page or let's
create a settings page let's call it
settings page
and the settings page can only be
accessed
by a admin
we're not going to do anything on the
page
but in here we are going to add the
author
the authorized attribute
and then
import namespace here and then specify
the policy
to be admin
only
right so this is the admin only policy
which we haven't configured yet
we're going to come over here and we're
going to add the admin only policy
okay so let's add the admin only policy
on the top the sequence doesn't really
matter here um i'm just thinking admin
is really one of the first to come to
mind so we're gonna
just
uh
specify on the top
and then here we're gonna say policy
again using lambda expression
we're going to i'm going to say policy
dot require claim
and then
you can see there is a signature which
only takes
the claim type and in this case it's
called main claim right and then
we have already applied this up in only
policy
on the
uh
settings page
right right over here the mean only
policy the next thing we need to do is
to in the login page
uh
we need to make sure
that we're gonna add
a another claim and this claims name is
admin and
well this dialog doesn't really matter
but let's set it to true we're going to
run control f5 and again
we're going to clear our cookie because
we didn't have a sign up page and i
didn't close my browser
so i'm gonna refresh this again coming
back to the
the login page try to log in again in
order to get the admin
claim so
now i have this cookie
newly generated and this should contain
our main claim
and now i can access
right i can access the settings page
without this claim
you won't have access to it let's see
what happens if we do that again delete
this cookie
refresh the page try to log in
go into index page now
manually navigate to the settings page
and now it says access denied right this
is exactly what's supposed to happen
and what if we create a human resource
manager page right so let's add a
another page and let's call it hr
manager
right so the hr manager page contains
you know some information or something
for the htm manager to do so this is the
ngr manager page and then here
we are going to specify a policy to be a
hr
manager only
something like that
okay so that's good and now let's
configure this policy and this hr
manager
is our manager manager only is that what
we specified
hr manager only and over here
again we're going to say policy
policy dot
require claim we're going to copy this
right and then we can chain it by saying
require claim
so let's change the format a little bit
so that it looks better
so when we chain it what we are really
seeing is that we need this claim to be
like this
and we need the next claim which is
a
manager claim to be present as well
right
so this is a end from this claim to this
claim is the end
relationship
so once we've done that
we can close this off and of course we
already had a department hr department
and then
the manager claim is not there if we're
running this just like that
without the manager claim we are
expecting to see access the night page
okay of course
first of all
i'm going to clear this cookie again f5
to see the login page and then input
your username and password click on the
login page
now
navigate to the
hr
manager page and
we see the access denied
right so in order to fix that we need to
go to our login page and over here
we are going to add
a
manager claim again the value doesn't
really matter because we're just
checking the presence of
the claim
but just to make it complete so we add a
true as the value
and then we're going to build it coming
back to here
delete this cookie and refresh the page
we're going to log in
now the cookie should have the manager
claim in it
it also has hr department claim in it
and we should be able to access
our
hr manager page just like that so we can
see the hr manager page so in this video
we have seen how we group different
claims into policy right we have simple
ones
and we have combinations
in the next video we are going to create
a more complicated case where we have
specific logic
right and then we would have to create
this requirement handler right the
authorization handler to specifically
handling that requirement right and
we're going to see it in the next video
if you have any questions please don't
hesitate to ask if not i'm going to see
you in the next one
so we have seen this cookie have been
always here
as long as if i keep the browser open
okay so even after i close the tab if i
have another
chrome browser open this cookie will
always stay in there so in this video
before we go any further let's implement
a sign out functionality so that we can
get rid of this cookie when we click on
the sign out button if we come to our
login page we can see that we have the
sign in async
extension method so this sign async
helped us to serialize the claims
principle right the security context
into a cookie similarly there is a sign
out async that can help us get rid of
the cookie so we can implement that in a
logout page let's go ahead and create a
logout page under the account folder
right razer page
let's simply call it logout
and for this page we don't need to have
any ui
the only thing we would need
is a on post method and of course it's
going to be on post async
because
we are going to
use cyanoasync
and then after that we need to do a
redirect so we need to implement this
very similar to the sign in method we'll
try to use the should be context the
sign out
async method this is not in http
contacts this is the extension method
we'll do a control dot
to import namespace from speed.net core
dot authentication
and then here we'll have a
authentication scheme name which is our
authentication scheme name we'll have to
specify
right like i said before it's better to
use a constant
for this in case we have a typo so but
for demonstration purpose i'm not going
to have it
so because we will need to do a redirect
that's why we need to have a wait there
so we're going to redirect to
our
index page
just like that
and that's it for our
logout page right we don't need a ui so
who's going to call this who's going to
trigger this on post
right so someone has to post to this
logo page
so for that we will need to create a
partial view we're going to put it in
the the layout page where we have this
header right we're gonna put it
somewhere here
for us to click the log out button
so
we can definitely just code it directly
in the layout page but we can also
create a partial view so i like to
create a partial view for that and for
creating a partial view it's really
really simple it's very similar to it's
almost the same as
in mvc so instead of using this add
razor page thing which currently doesn't
have a really good support for creating
partial view i'm just going to copy
this validation script partial i'm going
to paste it in here and then i'm going
to change
the the name to be underscore
login
let's call it login status
partial
okay and within here of course we don't
need this we'll need just some razor
syntax here well we're going to say
if the user
right if the user.identity
if the default energy is
authenticated right if it's not a
anonymous one then we're going to do
something otherwise if it is anonymous
identity then we'll do something else
let's implement the simplest case which
is the anonymous one so we're going to
have a link which just looks like a
a link button
and we're going to use
btn-link class
and
and then we're going to use tag helper
to link to a page
which is inside our account folder
and and it is the login page of course
and the label is logging and then here
when the user is authenticated we need
to allow user to click on a button to
log out right so for that we need to
have a form
right and the form
behavior is post
meaning
you know clicking on the submit button
in the forum will post to a certain page
and this form is going to use inline
class and it's going to be
linked to
the
log
logout page
right under the account folder
so
and we're gonna display a welcome
message first
we're welcoming the user to the system
uh use the default identity
and then we're gonna have a button
and the type is going to be a submit
button and the class
we're going to have a
little bit margin here
and same thing i'm going to use a link
button
and it's a logout as the label
when user click on this button
this is going to trigger http post and
then this is going to be post to the
logout page
which we have
just implemented here so
when this
page handler receives
the http post request
it's going to simply sign out which
means it's going to kill the cookie and
then redirect to the index page now we
have created this partial view we have
to use it in the layout
and we're going to use it right here
so first of all we'll have a div to wrap
around it and i'm going to use a class
so that
it's going to have uh it's going to
align to the right we're going to use
margin right
and then we're going to use the partial
the partial tag helper
to use our login status partial view
here
okay so we're all set and i'm doing ctrl
f5 okay so we have a login button here
but because the index page is already
protected so we're seeing the login page
anyways we don't have to click on the
login button and then i'm going to use
the password and now we're logged in
right
and if we go to our privacy page go to
our home page
this is there they're all working
correctly and then we are going to click
on the logout button while we are in the
privacy page click on the logout button
alright so this we expect us to kill the
cookie
all right so let's bring up the cookie
i can see the cookie right here
we expect this to kill the cookie and
also redirect us to the index page
but because the index page is protected
it will automatically redirect us again
to the
login page all right so this is what
happened you can see that the cookie is
deleted
and because the cookie is not present
anymore
when accessing any page the
authentication middleware will not be
able to pick up
the security context
so it will have a anonymous identity
which on any of our pages except privacy
page are not allowed
so that's the login status partial view
and logout functionality implemented
in later videos we're going to talk more
about the lifetime of a cookie and how
is it correlated with the broader
session but next video we'll continue
with authorization first
two videos ago we have implemented
simple authorization policies where
we're simply checking the existence of a
claim
or
specific values of claim in this video
we are going to implement some more
complicated scenarios where we're
checking some custom logic
other than just checking the presence of
a claim or the specific value of the
claim so let's imagine a scenario where
you are hired as
a human resource manager
and
you can access of course you can access
human resource manager page
whereas the permission
is only given when you pass your
probation period
right so for example you have a three
months probation period and within the
three months although you're giving the
main claim and uh hr department claim
you still haven't passed your probation
period you won't be able to access
the the page right so that's going to be
a
a customer requirement which we're going
to implement and then we have to
implement the authorization handler to
help us to handle the requirement and
then in the handler we can say whether
the security context satisfies the
requirement or not
okay so let's jump into video studio and
get started right away
so first of all let's go into our login
page
okay so here we will need some extra
claims here we need to have a claim
which contains the employment date
of the person who is logged in okay so
so the employment date let's say the
employment date is may 1st 2021
so 2021 0 5
1. so this is may 1st so we added this
claim the next step we need to create a
requirement
which we will create it under the
authorization folder so let's create a
authorization folder which will contain
all of our
custom requirement
right if we have many in this case we
only have one
but we'll still have it
in the folder
so we'll create a class
okay and we're going to call the class
hr
manager
probation
requirement
that sounds like a
meaningful name and for any requirement
we'll have to derive that requirement
from eye authorization requirement
interface
right eye authorization requirement
this interface doesn't have anything in
it if we go to the definition
right we can see it's empty
so the reason why we need it i'll
explain
why we need this
interface a little bit later
so in here
we're going to have
the probation
uh
period passed in right so probation
let's say probation month
uh i'm going to do control dot to
initialize it as a public property
right
so we have this public property here
and then inside the namespace we're
going to create the handler right here
okay so we're going to have a public
class
which
will have
this name so so it's not requirement
it's requirement
okay so
we'll have to change the name of the
file as well
so i'm going to copy this name and then
i'm just going to call it
hr manager permission requirement
handler and this will have to derive
from the
authorization
handler class
and here you can see
we have a t requirement and this t
requirement is a i authorization
requirement right so that's why we need
this i authorization requirement here
right although this is an empty
interface we just need it so that we can
have this handler
implemented properly
right so i put in this
requirement
here and then you can see the the red
squiggly line here i'm i'm just going to
ctrl dot to implement abstract class
okay so i hit enter so we'll have a a
virtual method overrated here
and we can we can see that this
requirement is passed in through this
method
right so we can implement this method
basically here we just need to get the
employment date and then you see whether
we have passed the probation period so
how do we get the
claim so we can check
in the context in here we can access the
user which
which is the claims principle right and
then it has has claimed a method here
and we can say
is there a claim whose type is
um
loy
meant date it's better we use a constant
for this name
but for demonstration purpose we're not
going to do that so
we can use the
if
condition statement here right so if it
doesn't exist
and this is when we need to
say we don't we don't say we fail
hey we don't need to
we just need to basically return
the empty task here the reason why we
don't want to
say it fails is that if it fails then
the policy will fail no matter what but
in some cases we want to have multiple
requirement within the policy so if one
of them satisfies then it's okay right
we don't want to return just a failure
like that so after this line we know
that we have a employment date claim so
we just need to get the the date here
right so we can use
daytime.parse
to parse the the claim
so we use the claim principle to find
our first
our first employment date claim and we
know we have it so we're pretty sure we
have it so then we can just access the
value and then we parse that so now we
have the employment date
uh and we just need to compare
the the differences right so the
preparation period
right the completion period is daytime
now
uh my minus
employment date
okay so
goes basically we're just going to say
if the period dot dot days
right so this
if you hover over you can see this is a
time span object so if the peer dot days
is greater than 30
times
requirement right we have our
preparation period preparation month
here so we can say requirement
dot provision month right because this
requirement is passing from here from
this parameter so we can just use that
and then
here we're going to say text dot succeed
we're going to call the succeed method
and then we want to make this particular
requirement succeed
okay and then after that we still return
an empty task
like that so now that we have the
requirement
and the handler we will need to go to
the startup class to register i'm going
to do control comma and start up
i need to go to startup.cs
and then we'll change this hr manager
policy a little bit we'll need to
add something here we're going to add
requirements
to this policy right so this is a
requirement which is requiring
the claim and this is also a claim
requirement and this is a customer
requirement and we just say dot
requirements dot add we're going to add
this
i authorization requirement right which
we already have implemented and from
here we can pass in the preparation
period right you can keep it in the
settings in the app settings if we want
but in this case for demonstration
purpose i'm going to hard code here so
three months
of probation period and then
we are going to do a control dot to
import the namespace we also need to
dependency inject this particular
requirements handler and for that we can
just add the handler to the service
collection right
and in this case we can use singleton or
we can use transit or scope it doesn't
really matter
but using singleton will improve the
performance just a little bit because it
does not need to recreate the class all
the time
right so i'm going to
do a control dot to import namespace
here and also the requirement
and blur
that's it
we have this requirement and this is
already on our hr manager page
right we don't have a hr manager page
menu
so let's just quickly add that
and that is in our layout page so let's
just add another
list item i have our hr manager page
here okay again coming back to this
diagram just so that we know exactly
what's happening so
if we're trying to access this hr
manager page right the authorization
middleware will grab the policy name and
then it will go through all of the
requirements and find their handlers
right because we have this handler
specified to handle that specific event
where we specified right here right so
this handler is kind of bond to this
requirement
so we have this handler to handle the
specific sorry not event the specific
requirement right therefore our
requirement handler will determine
whether the security contacts will
actually satisfy the requirements
all right so this is the theory and then
we have already implemented so let's
give it that a try i'm going to do a
ctrl f5
to run the application all right i'm
going to log in
i stay admin
and then i'm accessing the next page
uh
well i'm going to change the privacy
going to change the label here in the
layout
so this is not
privacy this is
hr
management
coming back refresh the page
all right so let's click on the hr
management
access denied why is access denied okay
so we can see that our requirement
actually has a 30 3 months configuration
here right
and in the login in the claim
uh the employment date is may 1st right
so that's from may 1st to today's date
which is may 15th
right so it's not going to work so if we
set it to february 1st then that's way
past three months so that should work
right so let's
give that a try
i'm going to do control
shift
b
all right build succeeded so let's first
log out to kill the cookie because the
cookie still contains may 1st as the
employment day so let's
just log out to kill the cookie and then
i'm going to log in again
so now the cookie is supposed to contain
february's first as the employment date
and if we go to the hr management page
we can see the hr manager page
right so
that is for this video where we have
implemented this
custom requirement and the customer
requirement handler
right so you can have pretty complicated
requirement and then all you have to do
just implement this authorization
handler to handle the specific
requirement
if you have any questions feel free to
ask
if not i'll see you in the next video
so once the login process finishes here
a cookie is generated as a
authentication ticket
the cookie may or may not have a expiry
date and time as developers we have the
power to choose to set the expiry date
in time or not
and that expiry date and time is also
affected by
broader session so in this video we are
going to talk about the lifetime of a
cookie and how it's affected by the
broader session
so like i said we can choose to control
the lifetime and the way to do so is to
come to the startup.cs
and then when we add a cookie
authentication handler we can come over
here and see options
right and then we can specify the expiry
time
span okay so we can say we're going to
expire in about
uh
let's say in about 30 seconds right so
if we do that
and then i'm gonna run ctrl i5 and i'm
going to log in and we watch the time
it may start at 45
so when it goes to 5 38 15 the
authentication ticket which is the the
cookie will expire now it comes to 15.
so if i go to for example this
or going back
see it does not work so as you can see
we can configure to have a lifetime
right and
when we have a lifetime the cookie will
expire
when the time comes
but what happens if we close the browser
before
the cookie expires let's try that
okay
so i'm going to
login and then right after this i'm
going to close the whole browser so i'm
going back to the page again
and as you can see we don't have a
cookie anymore
right because clothing the browser it
automatically deleted the cookie so how
is browser session affects the lifetime
of a cookie
let's talk about that now
first of all what is a broader session a
broader session is basically an
interaction
between
the browser and the server
right so
the browser session
lasts as long as the lifetime of the
browser so as soon as you close the
browser the session is finished so
that's the browser session
so if we draw two bars the first bar
represents the lifetime of the cookie
the second one represents
the left time of the session broader
session so how is the browser session
lifetime affects the the cookie lifetime
right
so if the browser's lifetime is longer
than the cookie lifetime basically it
does not affect the cookie's lifetime
the cookie will expire
when the time comes right
at this moment it will expire if the
brother session is shorter
than the cookie lifetime of course so
the cookie's actual lifetime is right
here
right because the browser is closed the
cookie is gone
right but there is a exception
where
you as a developer can set as a set a
cookie as a persistent cookie which
means that the cookie
will
survive the browser's closing so even
when the browser is closed the cookie
will still stay there so this is called
persistent cookie
right a persistent cookie will always
have the lifetime as you set for the
cookie let's say the browser is
closed here and then
after
some time the browser is open again this
time the session is a little bit longer
the broader session is a bit longer
the cookie will still expire at this
moment right there how so how do we set
a cookie as a persistent cookie you have
all experienced the login screen where
you see there's like keep me signed in
or remember me checkbox when you check
that checkbox
then the quickie becomes a persistent
cookie so let's implement that in in our
visual studio
so first of all we need a
model right page model that includes a
checkbox which is going to be a boolean
variable here right so we're going to
call it remember me
and then we're going to have a better
display name
with a space in between
so i'm going to say remember me
just like in coco
and then
we are going to
go to the login page here and then we
are going to add a
a row here right
let's say
this is going to be a row and then we're
going to use form check
okay and then we are going to have a
little bit margin at the bottom
uh because this is not a form con form
group right so it doesn't have enough
margin at the bottom so we're going to
add
a little bit margin there and then in
the like in between we're gonna have the
same thing here
and we are going to change this to a
check box this is going to be
a
data binding here and we're going to
bind to remember me
and then
the class is going to be form check
all right form check input
and it does not need to have a value
here
and then we'll need a label
for that
textbox checkbox okay and this is going
to be called form check label
and of course this is going to be for
the same field just remember me
and then that's it
right
so what's this we are going to receive
once it's posted
right the form is posted we're going to
receive that value in the credentials in
in the remember me field
so what we need to do is before we sign
the cookie right assign anyone create a
cookie
we need to have another variable that's
called
authorize the authentication properties
and we're going to create that
authentication
properties you can see this right here
and then there's a whole bunch of things
you can configure here one thing that is
important to us is this is persistent
thing
we're gonna
make it persistent only when the user
selected check the check box so when the
remember me is true
right so
we'll have this
authentication property
and then we're going to pass it as the
third parameter you can see that the
third parameter here is the
authentication property
right so with this let's give it a try
let's check double check what is the
30 seconds okay so we have a 30 seconds
cookie
that is too short for our experiment
because we want to try to close the
browser and then come back and see that
the cookie still works right so let's
have a two minutes
uh two minutes cookie first
and then i'm gonna do ctrl i five all
right so we're gonna log in and this
time i'm going to check remember me and
if i click i'm logged in right now
and then i'm going to close the browser
and i'm going to open it up again all
right so the browser is open you can see
that we're still we're still here we
don't have to log in
right our cookie is still here
oh no this one this one
our cookie is still here that is a
persistent cookie now the persistent
cookie is still subject to the expiry
date and to test that let's have a
shorter
cookie
which will change back
to
30 seconds lifetime
and then we are going to test that
okay so let's log in again
we're going to log in
and then immediately i'm going to close
the browser
and i'm going to open up the browser
again so i did this within 30 seconds so
i'm still locking
right so let's wait for another 15
seconds okay now if i refresh my screen
my cookie has already expired when i
refresh my screen i expect that i'm
kicked out because my cookie is not
valid anymore so
and i refresh my
screen i see my login page and that's
exactly what's supposed to be so
hopefully this video is helpful to help
you understand the relationship between
the cookie lifetime and broader session
lifetime so if you have any questions
please feel free to ask me and if not
i'll see you in the next video